我们今晚的面食是  柠檬草汁鱿鱼云吞
Our pasta this evening is squid ravioli in a lemon grass broth...
热羊乳酪夹心小酥球  还有芝麻菜凯撒沙拉
with goat cheese profiteroles, and I also have a rugula Caesar salad.
今晚的主菜  我们有箭鱼肉卷加洋葱酱
For entrees this evening, I have swordfish meatloaf with onion marmalade,
浅烤鹧鸪胸肉配红莓汁
rare roasted partridge breast in raspberry coulis
和酸模酱汁...
with a sorrel timbale.
还有烤自由放养兔肉  配草本法式薯条
and grilled free-range rabbit with herbed French fries.
我们今晚的面食是  柠檬草汁鱿鱼云吞
Our pasta tonight is squid ravioli in a lemon grass broth.
今晚的鱼是烧烤的...
and the fish tonight is...
再加一杯双份浓咖啡
We want double cup of espresso coffee.
天啊  我恨这个地方  都是女孩吃的东西
God, I hate this place. It's a chick's restaurant.
我们为什么不去多西亚餐厅?
Why aren't we at Dorsia?
因为贝特曼不答应
Because Bateman won't give the maitre d' head.
那边是里德·罗宾森吗?
Is that Reed Robinson over there?
你是不是嗑药了? 那不是罗宾森
Are you freebasing or what? That's not Robinson.
-那么  是谁呀? -那是保罗·艾伦
-Well, who is it then? -It's Paul Allen.
那不是保罗·艾伦  保罗·艾伦在屋子的那边
That's not Paul Allen. Paul Allen's on the other side of the room
-在那边  -和他在一起的是谁?
-over there. -Who's he with?
某个一起鬼混的人吧
Some weasel from Kicker Peabody.
他们要吸毒的话  这里的厕所可真不怎么样
They don't have a good bathroom to do coke in.
你确信那是保罗·艾伦?
Are you sure that's Paul Allen over there?
对  傻瓜  我确信
Yes, McDufus, I am.
他主管费舍帐户
He's handling the Fisher account.
-这混蛋真幸运  -这犹太混蛋真幸运
-Lucky bastard. -Lucky Jew bastard.
天啊  这有什么关系?
Jesus, McDermott, what does that have to do with anything?
我看到过混帐坐在他的办公室里
I've seen that bastard sitting in his office...
一边和首席执行官讲电话  一边在转一个可恨的灯台
talking on the phone to the C.E.O.s, spinnin' a fuckin' menorah.
不是灯台  转的是光明节陀螺
Not a menorah. You spin a dreidel.
我的天  贝特曼
Oh, my God, Bateman.
你想让我把你烤成土豆煎饼吗?
Do you want me to fry you up some fucking potato pancakes? Some latkes?
不  别说那些反对犹太人的话了
No, just... cool it with the anti-Semitic remarks.
我忘了  贝特曼正与美国  公民自由联盟的什么人谈恋爱
Oh, I forgot. Bateman's dating someone from the A.C.L.U.
他是理性之声  邻家男孩
He's the voice of reason. The boy next door.
讲到理性
Speaking of reasonable...
只要570美元
Only $570.
不坏啊
That's not bad.
给钱包小小滋润一下
A little something for the purse.
给她50美元小费
Give her the 50.
两杯  斯多利加冰
Stoli on the rocks.
我们不收这个  这是现钱交易的酒吧
These aren't good anymore. It's a cash bar.
25美元
That'll be $25.
你真是臭婊子
You're a fucking ugly bitch.
我要抽死你
I wanna stab you to death...
喝干你的血
and play around with your blood.
我能给二位来点什么?
What can I get for you two?
我住在美国花园大厦
I live in the American Gardens building...
西81街11楼
on West 81st Street on the 11th floor.
我叫帕特立克·贝特曼  我27岁
My name is Patrick Bateman. I'm 27 years old.
我深信保持仪表
I believe in taking care of myself,
平衡饮食的重要性
in a balanced diet,
坚守严格的锻炼计划
in a rigorous exercise routine.
早上  如果我的脸有些浮肿
In the morning, if my face is a little puffy,
我会一边做仰卧起坐一边敷冰
I'll put on an icepack while doing my stomach crunches.
我现在能做1000个了
I can do a thousand now.
在取下冰袋后  我使用一种深层毛孔清洁润肤露
After I remove the icepack, I use a deep pore cleanser lotion.
淋浴的时候  我是用一种水性凝胶浴液
In the shower, I use a water-activated gel cleanser.
然后用蜂蜜杏仁磨沙膏
Then a honey-almond body scrub.
脸上  用一种透气胶质磨沙膏
And on the face, an exfoliating gel scrub.
然后我敷上一种草药薄荷面膜
Then I apply an herb mint facial masque,
停留10分钟
which leave on for ten minutes
同时我会为其他的程序做准备
while I prepare the rest of my routine.
我总是用一种须后水
I always use an aftershave lotion
含酒精很少或者没有
with little or no alcohol,
因为酒精会让你的皮肤干燥
because alcohol dries your face out
让我看上去更老
and makes you look older.
然后是滋润霜
Then moisturizer,
然后是抗衰老眼霜
then an anti-aging eye balm,
之后是最后一层保护性润肤霜
followed by a final moisturizing protective lotion.
这就是帕特立克·贝特曼的形象
There is an idea of a Patrick Bateman.
有些抽象
Some kind of abstraction,
但真实的我是没有的
but there is no real me.
只是一个代号  有些虚幻
Only an entity... something illusory.
尽管我能够隐藏起冰冷的目光
And though I can hide my cold gaze...
你能握我的手  感到肉体的接触
and you can shake my hand and feel flesh gripping yours...
也许你甚至能感到
and may be you can even sense
我们的生活方式有很多类似之处
our life styles are probably comparable,
但我根本心不在焉
I simply am not there.
早上好  汉密尔顿  肤色晒得很好看
Good morning, Hamilton. Nice tan.
-晚了  -有氧运动课  对不起  有口信吗?
-Late. -Aerobics class. Sorry. Any messages?
里奇·哈里森得取消了
Ricky Harrison has to cancel.
他没有说取消什么  为什么取消
He didn't say what he was cancelling or why.
我偶尔和里奇在哈佛俱乐部拳击  还有谁吗?
I occasionally box with Ricky at the Harvard Club. Anyone else?
斯宾塞希望约你在福露蒂的  第17号码头见面喝酒
Spencer wants to meet for drinks at Fluties, Pier 17.
-什么时候? -6点以后
-When? -After 6:00.
-不行  取消  -我应该说什么?
-Negative. Cancel it. -And what should I say?
-就说不行  -就说不行?
-Just say "no" -Just say "no"?
好了  姬恩
Okay, Jean.
我需要预订  三个人  在卡莫斯餐厅  12点半
I need reservations for three at Camols at 12:30,
如果那里不行  试试大峡谷餐厅  好吗?
and if not there try Crayons.
好的  先生
All right? Yes, sir.
等等  我要订一个两人桌
Oh, wait. And I need reservations for two
阿卡迪亚餐厅  星期四晚8点
at Arcadia at 8:00 on Thursday.
浪漫的事儿?
Something romantic?
不是
No.
真傻
Silly.
忘了吧  我来订
Forget it. I'll make them.
-不  我来做  -不  不
-No, I'll do it. -No, no.
乖乖  给我拿瓶矿泉水  好吗?
Be a doll and just get me a mineral water, okay?
你今天很漂亮
You look nice today.
别再穿那套衣服了
Don't wear that outfit again.
什么? 我没听见
What? I didn't hear you.
我说  别再穿那套衣服了
I said, do not wear that outfit again.
穿条裙子  短裙什么的
Wear a dress, a skirt or something.
你不喜欢这个  对吗?
You don't like this, I take it.
别了  你本来应该更漂亮的
Come on. You're prettier than that.
谢谢  帕特立克
Thanks, Patrick.
和人说我不在
I'm not here.
还有高跟鞋  我喜欢高跟鞋
And high heels. I like high heels.
600人的"羽毛朋友"
Feathered friends for 600.
在求偶过程中  雄性军舰鸟
During courtship, the male frigate bird...
喉囊会庞然鼓起  呈鲜红色
inflates to enormous size the red pouch found here.
成千上万朵玫瑰
And I want hundreds of thousands of roses.
很多很多高迪瓦松露巧克力
And lots of chocolate truffles,
剥开半扇的牡蛎
Godiva, and oysters in the half shell.
我试图聆听新的罗伯特·帕尔玛的磁带
I'm trying to listen to the new Robert Palmer tape,
但伊芙琳  我所谓的未婚妻
but Evelyn, my supposed fiance,
不停地在我耳边聒噪
keeps buzzing in my ear.
安妮·雷伯维茨  我们要请来安妮·雷伯维茨
Annie Leibovitz. We'll get Annie Leibovitz.
我们必须找个人来拍录像带
And we'll have to get someone to videotape.
帕特立克  我们应该这么做
Patrick, we should do it.
-做什么? -结婚  举行婚礼
-Do what? -Get married. Have a wedding.
不  我上班抽不出时间
No. I can't take the time off work.
你父亲实际上拥有这家公司  你爱干什么都行  傻瓜
Your father practically owns the company. You can do anything you like, silly.
我不想谈这事儿
I don't want to talk about it.
而且你憎恨这份工作  我不懂你为什么不辞职
I hate that job anyway. I don't see why you just don't quit.
因为我想让自己适应
Because I want to fit in.
电子空间
威廉姆斯的聚会
Williams party.
我们到达电子空间的时候  我眼泪都快掉下来了
I'm on the verge of tears by the time we arrive at Espace,
因为我确信我们的桌子不会很好
since I'm positive we won't have a decent table.
但桌子很好
But we do, and relief washes over me
我立即如释重负
in an awesome wave.
帕特立克  这是我的表妹凡登  和她的男朋友斯塔什
Patrick, this is my cousin Vanden and her boyfriend Stash.
他们都是艺术家
They're both artists.
-菜单是用盲文写的  -你已经见到所有人了  很好
-The menu's in Braille. -I see you've met everyone.
你看上去很漂亮
You look awful.
好吧  好吧
Okay. All right.
我相当肯定  蒂莫西·布莱斯和伊芙琳在私通
I'm fairly certain that... Timothy Bryce and Evelyn are having an affair.
蒂莫西是我认识的唯一风趣的人
Timothy is the only interesting person I know.
我几乎毫不关心
I'm almost completely indifferent
伊芙琳是否知道我有外遇
as to whether Evelyn knows...
而且是和她最亲密的朋友考特尼·劳林森
I'm having an affair with Courtney Rawlinson, her closest friend.
考特尼长相几乎完美
Courtney is almost perfect looking.
她通常需要吃一种或者以上的  精神病药物才能运转正常
She's usually operating on one or more psychiatric drugs.
今晚  我相信吃的是阿普唑仑
Tonight, I believe, it's Xanax. Mmm. Oh.
但比她使用药物更加让人烦恼的是
More disturbing than her drug use,
她已经订婚了
though, is the fact that she's engaged...
未婚夫是路易斯·卡鲁瑟斯  最大的傻瓜
to Luis Carruthers, the biggest doofus in the business.
告诉我  斯塔什
Tell me, Stash.
你觉得苏豪区变得太商业化了吗?
Do you think Soho is becoming too... commercial?
对  我在报纸上读到了
Yes. I read that.
谁关心这个呢?
Oh, who gives a rat's ass?
这影响到了我们
Hey, that affects us.
斯里兰卡的大屠杀呢  亲爱的?
Well, what about the massacres in Sri Lanka, honey? Doesn't that affect us too?
那个不也影响到我们了吗? 你对斯里兰卡知道多少?
Do you know anything about Sri Lanka?
比如说  锡克族怎么会在那里  杀那么多以色列人?
How, like, the Sikhs are killing tons of Israelis over there?
别这样  布莱斯
Come on, Bryce.
还有很多比斯里兰卡  更重要的问题要担心呢
There are a lot more important problems than Sri Lanka to worry about.
比如?
Like what?
比如  我们必须结束种族隔离
Well, we have to end apartheid, for one,
放缓核军备竞赛的速度
slow down the nuclear arms race,
制止恐怖主义和世界饥饿问题
stop terrorism and world hunger.
我们必须为无家可归者提供食宿
We have to provide food and shelter for the homeless...
反对种族歧视  促进民权
and oppose racial discrimination and promote civil rights,
同时促进妇女享有平等权利
while also promoting equal rights for women.
我们要鼓励回归
We have to encourage a return...
传统道德价值观
to traditional moral values.
更重要的是
Most importantly,
我们必须促进普遍的社会关怀
we have to promote general social concern...
在年轻人中减少物质主义倾向
and less materialism in young people.
帕特立克
Patrick,
真是发人深省
how thought provoking.
你好
Hello.
"漂白"? 你是想说"漂白"?
Bleaching? Are you trying to say "bleaching"?
我的天  两件事
Oh, my God. Two things.
第一件  你不能漂白切瑞蒂衣服  就是不能
One: You can't bleach a Cerruti. Out of the question.
第二件  我只能从圣塔菲买这些床单
Two: I can only get these sheets in Santa Fe.
这些都是非常昂贵的床单  自然要洗得非常干净
These are very expensive sheets, and I really need them cleaned.
如果你不闭上你的臭嘴
Lady, if you don't shut your fucking mouth,
我就杀了你
I will kill you.
20分钟后我在胡伯特饭店  与罗纳德·哈里森有个午餐会议
Now, listen. I have a lunch meeting at Hubert's in 20 minutes with Ronald Harrison.
我需要今天下午前把这些床单洗好
I need those sheets cleaned by this afternoon.
我不理解你! 这真是疯了  你是个傻瓜
Listen, I can't understand you! This is crazy! You're a fool.
我对付不了了  愚蠢的"漂白妇"!
I can't cope with this stupid "bitchee"!
懂了吗? 天啊
Understand? Christ. Patrick?
帕特立克?
Hi, Patrick.
帕特立克  我以为是你
I thought that was you.
你好...
Hello. This is...
一路上来奇怪吗?
Isn't it ridiculous, coming all the way up here?
但他们真是最好的
They really are the best.
那么他们怎么连这些污渍都没洗掉?
Then why can't they get these stains out?
你能和这些人讲讲吗? 我讲不通
I mean, can you talk to these people or something? I'm not getting anywhere.
那些是什么?
Oh, what are those?
好吧  这是红莓汁  红莓苹果汁
Well, it's... Cranberry juice. Cranapple.
真的?
Really?
听着  如果你能和他们谈谈  我非常感谢
Listen, if you could talk to them, I would really appreciate it.
我真的晚了  15分钟后我在胡伯特餐厅  约了个午餐
I'm really late. I have a lunch appointment at Hubert's in 15 minutes.
胡伯特餐厅? 他们搬到上城区了  对吗?
Hubert's? That moved uptown, right? Oh, boy.
听着  我要走了  谢谢你  维多利亚
Listen, I've gotta go. Thank you, Victoria.
也许我们下周能吃顿午饭
Maybe we could do lunch one day next week.
你知道  我在下城区住...
I'm downtown quite often.
-不行  我整天都工作  -星期六怎么样?
-I'm at work all the time. -What about a Saturday?
-下周六? -好吧
-Next Saturday?  -Sure.
恐怕不行  我要去看《悲惨世界》
Can't, I'm afraid. At a matinee of LesMis.
我真得走了  天啊  我给你打电话
Listen, I really gotta go. Oh, Christ. I'll call you.
好  走吧
Okay. Do.
听着  你和路易斯谈恋爱  但他在亚利桑那州
Listen, you're dating Lewis, he's in Arizona.
你在和我做爱  我们还没订计划呢
You're fucking me, and we haven't made plans.
今晚你能干什么呢?
What could you possibly be up to tonight?
-住嘴  我... -服用大量的锂?
-Stop it. I'm... -On a lot of lithium?
等着路易斯给我打电话
Waiting for Luis to call me.
他说他今晚会打的
He said he'd call tonight.
小傻瓜
Pumpkin?
小傻瓜  你在和一个混球谈恋爱
Pumpkin, you're dating an asshole.
小傻瓜  你在和纽约最大的混蛋谈恋爱
Mm-hmm. Pumpkin, you're dating the biggest dickweed in New York.
小傻瓜  你在和非常  非常混的混蛋谈恋爱
Pumpkin, you're dating a tumbling, tumbling dickweed.
帕特立克  别叫我小傻瓜了  好吗?
Patrick, stop calling me pumpkin, okay?
-我必须走了  -考特尼!
-I have to go. -Courtney?
-晚餐  -我不能
-Hmm? Dinner. -I can't.
我想去多西亚
I'm thinking Dorsia.
多西亚很好
Dorsia's nice.
穿漂亮些
Wear something fabulous.
纽约市餐厅
多西亚
Dorsia.
对  我知道有些晚了
Um, yes, I know it's a little late,
还有可能预订一个两人桌吗?
but is it possible to reserve a table for two
8点或者8点半  怎么样?
at 8:00 or 8:30, perhaps?
在伊丽莎白·雅顿做个脸  真正放松一下
a facial at Elizabeth Arden, which was really relaxing.
然后去陶器坊
And then, to the Pottery Barn,
我买了这个小蛋糕碟
where I got this little silver muffin dish.
那是多纳德·特拉普的车吗?
Is that Donald Trump's car?
天啊  帕特立克  闭嘴
God, Patrick. Shut up.
考特尼  你应该来点儿锂  或者一瓶健怡可乐
You know, Courtney, you should take some more lithium or have a Diet Coke.
来点儿咖啡因会让你不这么懒散
Some caffeine might get you out of this slump.
我就想要个小孩
I just want a child.
就两个
Just two...
完美的
perfect...
孩子
children.
我们还在这里吗?
Are we here?
对
Yeah.
这是多西亚吗?
This is Dorsia?
-晚上好  -是的  亲爱的
-Good evening! -Yes, dear.
考特尼  你要来份花生酱汤
Courtney, you're gonna have the peanut butter soup...
配熏鸭和窝瓜泥
with smoked duck and mashed squash.
《纽约马提尼》杂志称之为
New York Matinee called it
"一道看似游戏  实则神秘的小菜"
"a playful but mysterious little dish."
你会喜欢的
You'll love it.
然后是红鲷鱼配紫罗兰和松子
And then the red snapper with violets and pine nuts.
我想这会衔接得很好
I think that'll follow nicely.
谢谢  帕特立克
Mmm. Thanks, Patrick.
帕特立克  非常感谢你照顾考特尼
Patrick, thanks so much for looking after Courtney.
多西亚  真棒啊
Dorsia. How impressive.
你究竟是怎样在那里订到桌的?
How on Earth did you get a reservation there?
幸运吧  我猜
Lucky, I guess.
这西装真棒
That's a wonderful suit.
别告诉我  让我猜猜
Don't tell me. Don't tell me. Let me guess.
瓦兰蒂诺高级成衣
Mmm, Valentino Couture?
看上去真柔软
Uh-huh. Hmm.
你的奉承足够了  路易斯
It looks so soft. Your compliment was sufficient, Luis.
你好  哈尔博斯特拉姆  领带很好看
Hello, Halberstram. Nice tie.
你究竟怎么啦?
How the hell are you?
艾伦把我当成傻瓜  马克斯·哈尔博斯特拉姆了
Allen has mistaken me for this dickhead, Marcus Halberstram.
这似乎有道理  因为马克斯  也在皮尔斯和皮尔斯工作
It seems logical because Marcus also works at P&P,
实际上  做的事情和我一模一样
and in fact does the same exact thing I do.
他也爱好瓦伦蒂诺西装和奥里佛人眼镜
He also has a penchant for Valentino suits and Oliver Peoples glasses.
马克斯和我甚至去同一家理发馆
Marcus and I even go to the same barber,
虽然我的发型稍微好一点儿
although I have a slightly better haircut.
那么  兰森帐户如何了  马克斯?
How's the Ransom account going, Marcus?
-挺好的  -真的?
-It's, uh, all right. -Really?
很有趣  不... 不很好
That's interesting. It's not, uh, not great.
-你知道  -那么塞西里亚如何? 她是个好姑娘
-Oh, well, you know. -So, how's Cecilia? She's a great girl.
我非常幸运
Oh, yeah. I'm very lucky.
艾伦  祝贺你拿到费舍帐户
Hey, Allen, congratulations on the Fisher account.
谢谢你  巴克斯特
Thank you, Baxter.
听着  保罗  打壁球吗?
Listen, Paul. Squash.
给我打电话
Call me.
-星期五如何? -不行
-How about Friday? -No can do.
我8点半在多西亚有个饭局
I got an 8:30 res at Dorsia.
海鲈鱼色拉很好
Great sea urchin ceviche.
星期五晚上在多西亚? 他在胡诌什么?
Dorsia on Friday night? How'd he swing that?
我想他在撒谎
I think he's lying.
那是一克吗?
Is that a gram?
新卡
New card.
你觉得如何?
What do you think?
皮尔斯和皮尔斯事务所  帕特立克·贝特曼  副总裁
非常好
Whoa-ho. Very nice.
看看那个
Look at that.
昨天从印刷厂取来的
Picked them up from the printer's yesterday.
-颜色很好  -那是骨质的
-Good coloring. -That's bone.
字体叫做希联轨
And the lettering is something called Silian Rail.
非常酷  贝特曼
It's very cool, Bateman,
这没什么  看看这个
but that's nothing. Look at this.
皮尔斯和皮尔斯事务所  戴维·冯·帕顿  副总裁
这真好看
That is really nice.
蛋青色加罗马字体
Eggshell with Romalian type.
你怎么看?
What do you think?
好看
Nice.
天啊  真是超级好
Jesus. That is really super.
你这个傻瓜怎么这么有品位?
How'd a nitwit like you get so tasteful?
我不能相信
I can't believe that Bryce...
布莱斯更喜欢冯·帕顿的名片
prefers Van Patten's card to mine.
但等等  你还没见过呢
But wait. You ain't seen nothin' yet.
突出字体  淡淡的灰白
Raised lettering, pale nimbus... white.
皮尔斯和皮尔斯事务所  蒂莫西·布莱斯  副总裁
非常好  很好看
Impressive. Very nice.
让我们看看保罗·艾伦的名片
Let's see Paul Allen's card.
皮尔斯和皮尔斯事务所  保罗·艾伦  副总裁
看看这细腻的浅白色彩印
Look at that subtle off-white coloring.
有品位的厚度
The tasteful thickness of it.
我的天
Oh, my God.
甚至还有水印呢
It even has a watermark.
有什么不对吗  帕特立克?
Is something wrong, Patrick?
你在出汗
You're sweating.
你好
Hello.
帕特·贝特曼  你要点儿钱吗?
Pat Bateman. You want some, uh, money?
来点吃的?
Some food?
-就要这个? -我饿了
-Is this what you need? -I'm... I'm hungry.
对  还冷极了  对吗?
Yeah. Cold out too, isn't it?
你为什么不找份工作呢?
Why don't you get a job?
如果你这么饿  为什么不找份工作?
If you're so hungry, why don't you get a job?
我失业了
I lost my job.
为什么? 你喝酒了?
Why? You drinking?
是因为这个丟了饭碗?
Is that why you lost it?
内部交易? 我开玩笑呢
Insider trading? Just joking.
-听着  你叫什么? -艾尔
-Listen, what's your name? -Al.
大声点  好不好
Hmm? Speak up. Come on.
-艾尔  -找份工  艾尔
-Al. -Get a goddamn job, Al.
你态度消极  这让你停步不前
You got a negative attitude. That's what's stopping you.
你要像那么回事儿
You gotta get your act together.
我来帮你
I'll help you.
您真好心  先生
You are so kind, mister.
您真好心  您是个好人
You're a kind... You're a kind man.
-没什么  -我看得出
-It's okay. -I can tell.
求求你  你要告诉我做什么
Please, you gotta tell me what to do.
你一定要帮我  我特别冷
You gotta help me. I'm so cold,
我饿了
I'm hungry.
你知道你有多难闻吗?
You know how bad you smell?
你浑身恶臭  你知道吗?
You reek of shit. Do you know that?
艾尔
Al.
对不起
I'm sorry.
就是... 我不知道
It's just that... I don't know.
我和你没有任何共同点
I don't have anything in common with you.
谢谢你  先生  谢谢你
Oh. Oh, thank you, mister. Thank you.
我这里很冷
I'm cold out here.
-你知道你真是失败啊  -什么?
-You know what a fucking loser you are? -What?
你的皮肤真好  贝特曼先生
What beautiful skin you have, Mr. Bateman.
这么细腻  这么光滑
So fine, so smooth.
我有着人类的所有特征
I have all the characteristics of a human being...
血肉发肤
flesh, blood, skin, hair...
但感情却都牵扯不清
but not a single, clear, identifiable emotion,
除了贪婪和厌恶
except for greed and disgust.
我身体的内部正在发生可怕的变化
Something horrible is happening inside of me,
我不知道为什么
and I don't know why.
夜晚奔腾在我血液里的欲望  白天也充斥了我
My nightly bloodlust has overflowed into my days.
我感到自己处于致命的疯狂边缘
I feel lethal, on the verge of frenzy.
我觉得我的正人君子的面具就要撕破了
I think my mask of sanity is about to slip.
麦克洛伊  你怎么说?
Hey, Mc Cloy, what do you say?
汉密尔顿  祝你圣诞快乐
Hey, Hamilton. Have a holly, jolly Christmas.
艾伦还在打理费舍帐户吗?
Is Allen still handling the Fisher account?
当然  除了他还有谁?
Of course. Who else?
槲寄生警报  圣诞快乐  帕特立克
Mistletoe alert. Merry Xmas, Patrick.
-圣诞快乐  哈里  -圣诞快乐
-Merry Xmas, Harry. -Merry Christmas.
-你晚了  亲爱的  -我没晚
-You're late, honey. -I'm not late.
-你晚了  -我一直都在这儿
-Oh, yes, you are. -I've been here the entire time.
你就是没看到我
You just didn't see me.
向雪人问好
Say hello to Snowball.
雪人说 "圣诞快乐  帕特立克"
Snowball says, "Merry Christmas, Patrick."
这是什么?
What is it?
是个小猪猪吧?
It's a little baby piggly-wiggly, isn't it?
是个越南小猪扑满
It's a Vietnamese potbellied pig.
它们真是可爱的宠物  是吗?
They make darling pets. Don't you?
不是吗?
Don't you?
别缠人了  帕特立克  你真像格林驰
Stop scowling, Patrick. You're such a grinch.
格林驰先生圣诞节想要什么?
And what does Mr. Grinch want for Christmas?
不要再说"乳房增大术"了
And don't say breast implants again.
-艾伦  -马克斯! 圣诞快乐
-Allen. -Marcus. Merry Christmas.
你好吗  工作狂?
How you been? Workaholic, I suppose?
我们好久没见了
Haven't seen you in a while.
汉密尔顿! 我们去乃尔饭店  豪华房车就在前门
Hey, Hamilton. We're goin' to Nell's. Limo's out front.
我们应该吃晚饭
We should have dinner.
也许您能带...
Maybe you could bring...
-塞西里亚? -对  塞西里亚
-Cecilia? -Yes, Cecilia.
塞西里亚会喜欢的
Oh, Cecilia would adore it.
那我们就这么做吧  马克斯
Well, then, let's do it, Marcus.
-聚会很好  -谢谢
-Great party. -Thanks.
帕特立克  为什么他叫你马克斯?
Patrick, why is he calling you Marcus?
槲寄生警报
Mistletoe alert.
马克斯·哈尔博斯特拉姆  7点两个人
Marcus Halberstram for two at 7:00.
不  我想知道
No, I want to know, okay?
我来此是为了吃  芫荽小龙虾秋葵汤的  好吗?
I came here for the cilantro crawfish gumbo,
毕竟  这是我来此餐厅的唯一理由
which is, after all, the only excuse one could have for being in this restaurant,
顺便说一句  几乎都是空的
which is, by the way, almost completely empty.
-非常对不起  先生  -J&B直瓶和科罗那啤酒
-I'm very sorry, sir. -J&B straight, and a Corona.
-你想听听... -双倍伏特加的马提尼
-Would you like to hear... -Double Absolute martini.
好的  先生  您想听听我们的特别推荐吗?
Yes, sir. Would you like to hear the specials?
不  如果你还想保全你的脾脏的话
Not if you want to keep your spleen.
这里真是如马蜂窝一般繁忙啊  哈尔博斯特拉姆
This is a real beehive of activity, Halberstram. This place is hot.
这个地方很热
Very hot. Listen, the mud soup and charcoal arugula...
听着  这里的泥汤和炭烧小牛肉棒极了
are outrageous here.
对了  你迟到了
Yeah, well, you're late.
我父母是离异的  放我一马吧
Hey, I'm a child of divorce. Give me a break.
我看到他们忽略了猪里脊配柠檬冻
I see they've omitted the pork loin with lime Jell-O.
我们早该去多西亚了
We should've gone to Dorsia.
我本来能搞到桌子的
I could've gotten us a table.
现在没人去那儿了
Nobody goes there anymore.
那是艾瓦纳·特拉普吗?
Is that Ivana Trump?
天啊  帕特立克... 我是说  马克斯
Oh, geez, Patrick. I mean, Marcus.
你在想什么?
What are you thinking?
为什么艾瓦纳会在得克萨斯?
Why would Ivana be at Texarkana?
原来不是罗斯柴尔德负责费舍帐户吗?
So, uh, wasn't Rothchild originally handling the Fisher account?
你怎么知道的?
How'd you get it?
我可以告诉你  哈尔博斯特拉姆
Well, I could tell you that, Halberstram,
但之后我就要杀了你
but then I'd have to kill you.
我喜欢肢解姑娘
I like to dissect girls.
你知道我完全疯了吗?
Did you know I'm utterly insane?
晒黑得很好看  马克斯  真不错
Great tan, Marcus. I mean, really impressive.
-你在哪里晒黑的? -美容院
-Where do you tan? -Salon.
我在家里有个阳光床  你应该看看
I've got a tanning bed at home. You should look into it.
塞西里亚... 她怎么样?
And, uh, Cecilia. How is she?
她今晚在哪儿?
Where is she tonight?
塞西里亚是... 你认识塞西里亚
Cecilia is, uh... Well, you know Cecilia.
我想她和伊芙琳·威廉姆斯一起吃晚饭
I think she's having dinner with, um, Evelyn Williams.
伊芙琳! 屁股很好看
Evelyn? Great ass.
在与那个失败的家伙  帕特立克·贝特曼谈恋爱
Goes out with that loser Patrick Bateman.
真是混蛋
What a dork.
再来杯马提尼? 保罗?
Another martini, Paul?
你喜欢修·刘易斯和新闻?
You like Huey Lewis and the News?
他们还行
Um, they're okay.
他们的早期作品对我来说  有些太新潮了
They're early work was a little too new wave for my taste.
但自从83年《运动》推出后
But when Sports came out in '83,
我想他们在商业上和艺术上  都找到了自我
I think they really came into their own, commercially and artistically.
整个专辑音响清晰干脆
The whole album has a clear, crisp sound,
一种新的完善专业精神
and a new sheen of consummate professionalism...
给予这些歌曲极大的促进
that really gives the songs a big boost.
人们将他比作艾维斯·卡斯提洛
He's been compared to Elvis Costello,
但我觉得修具有一种更加  尖刻  讥讽的幽默
but I think Huey has a far more bitter, cynical sense of humor.
-哈尔博斯特拉姆  -怎么  艾伦?
-Hey, Halberstram? -Yes, Allen?
为什么《时尚》版到处都是?
Why are there copies of the Style section all over the place?
你有狗吗?
Do you... Do you have a dog?
小哈巴狗什么的?
A little chow or something?
-没有  艾伦  -那是雨衣吗?
-No, Allen. -Is that a raincoat?
对了!
Yes, it is.
87年  修发行了
In '87, Huey released this...
他们最具成就的专辑《Fore!》
Fore, their most accomplished album.
我认为他们毫无争议的杰作是《宁折不弯》
I think their undisputed masterpiece is "Hip To Be Square."
这首歌  曲调非常吸引人  大部分人很可能都不用听歌词了
The song's so catchy, most people probably don't listen to the lyrics.
但他们还应该听  因为这不仅
But they should, because it's not just about...
是一致的享受  不仅关系到  趋势的重要性
the pleasures of conformity and the importance of trends.
这也是乐队本身的自我宣言
It's also a personal statement about the band itself.
保罗?
Hey, Paul!
现在试着在多西亚订个位
Try getting a reservation at Dorsia now,
你这个愚蠢的混帐!
you fuckin' stupid bastard!
你这个混帐!
You fucking bastard!
#因为我知道会发生什么#
#Because I can tell what's going on#
#宁折不弯#
#It's hip to be a square#
It's hip to be a square
#我喜欢让我的乐队成员穿西装#
#I like my bands in business suits#
#我在电视上看到他们#
#I watch them on TV#
#我每天都锻炼身体#
#I'm working out most everyday#
#注意饮食#
#and watching what I eat#
#他们告诉我这对我有好处#
#They tell me that it's good for me#
#但我根本不在意#
#but I don't even car#
#我知道这很疯狂#
#I know that it's crazy#
#我知道这没有出路#
#I know that it's nowhere#
#不容否认的是#
#But there is no denying that#
#我宁折不弯#
#It's hip to be a square#
他站着的时候完全赤裸
He was completely naked and standing up on the table.
站在一张桌子上  人人都看着...
He had no clothes on what so ever, and he...
帕特立克? 帕特立克!
Patrick? Patrick.
是你吗?
Is that you?
不  路易斯  不是我  你搞错了
No, Luis, it's not me. You're mistaken.
这是我非常要好的朋友  帕特立克·贝特曼
This is my very good friend, Patrick Bateman.
你去哪儿? 我们去奈尔斯餐厅
Where are you going? We're going to Nell's.
关多琳的父亲来付帐
Gwendolyn's father is buying it.
你从哪儿买的过夜旅行包?
Where did you get that overnight bag?
保罗·古蒂尔那
Jean-Paul Gaultier.
我去到了保罗·艾伦的住处
When I get to Paul Allen's place,
我用的钥匙是处理尸体前  从他兜里拿的
I use the keys I took from his pocket... before disposing of the body.
真是无比紧张
There is a moment of sheer panic...
我当时意识到保罗的公寓  能够俯瞰公园
when I realize that Paul's apartment overlooks the park...
显然要比我的贵
and is obviously more expensive than mine.
我让自己冷静  进入卧室
I calm myself and move into the bedroom,
我发现了他的旅行包  开始装行李
where I find his suitcase and start to pack.
保罗要小小旅行一下了
It's time for Paul to take a little trip.
把这个混帐送哪儿呢?
Where do I send the bastard?
达勒斯?
Dallas?
巴黎? 新加坡?
Paris? Singapore?
伦敦  我要把这个家伙送到伦敦
London? I'll send the asshole to London.
这是保罗
Hi. This is Paul.
我应召去伦敦几天
I've been called away to London for a few days.
玛瑞蒂斯  我回来给你打电话
Meredith, I'll call you when I get back.
再见  宝贝
Hasta la vista, baby.
这是什么?
What is it?
帕特立克
Patrick.
怎么啦  姬恩?
Yes, Jean?
有个叫唐纳德·金鲍尔先生来见您
There's a Mr. Donald Kimball here to see you.
谁?
Who?
侦探唐纳德·金鲍尔
Detective Donald Kimball.
告诉他我去吃午饭了
Tell him I'm at lunch.
帕特立克  刚10点半  我想他知道你在这儿
Patrick, it's only 10:30. I think he knows you're here.
那就让他进来吧
Send him in, I guess.
现在  约翰  你必须穿合体的衣服
Now, John, you've gotta wear clothes in proportion to your physique.
规规矩矩的  好兄弟  穿明条衬衫要守规矩
There are definite do's and don'ts, good buddy, of wearing a bold-striped shirt.
一件鲜明条纹衬衫需要配颜色沉稳
A bold-striped shirt calls for solid-colored...
或者有暗纹的西装和领带
or discreetly patterned suits and ties.
对了  总是付给发型师15%小费
Yes, always tip the stylist 15 percent.
听着  约翰  我要走了  尖骨鸡刚刚进来了
Listen, John, I've gotta go. T. Boone Pickens just walked in.
开玩笑呢
Just joking.
不  不要给美容院老板小费
No, don't tip the owner of the salon.
好了  约翰  对  懂了
Okay, John? Right. Got it.
对不起
Sorry about that.
不  我要说对不起  我应该约个时间
No, I'm sorry. I should've made an appointment.
有什么重要的事情吗?
Was that anything important?
那个? 就是解决商业问题
Oh, that? Just mulling over business problems,
研究机会  交换谣言
examining opportunities, exchanging rumors,
传播小道消息
spreading gossip.
我是唐纳德·金鲍尔
I'm Donald Kimball.
帕特·贝特曼  很高兴见到您
Pat Bateman. Nice to meet you.
对不起冒昧打搅  我知道你们都很忙
Sorry to barge in on you like this. I know how busy you guys can get.
那么  讨论的题目是什么?
So, what's the, uh, topic of discussion?
我是美瑞蒂斯·鲍威尔雇用的
I've been hired by Meredith Powell...
前来调查保罗·艾伦的失踪
to investigate the disappearance of Paul Allen.
我懂了  保罗的失踪  对啊
I see, yeah. Paul's disappearance, yeah.
所以一点都不正式  我就要问有关保罗·艾伦的一些基本问题
So it's nothing that official. I just have some questions about Paul Allen
-关于你自己... -咖啡?
-and yourself. -Coffee?
不必了  我很好
No, I'm okay.
-阿波里纳斯矿泉水? -我很好  不必了
-Apollinaris? -No, I'm okay.
-你能给那位先生... -金鲍尔
-Can you bring Mr... -Kimball.
金鲍尔先生一瓶...
Mr. Kimball a bottle of Apollinaris.
-不  真的  我很好  -没问题
-No, I'm okay. -It's no problem.
好吧  讨论的题目是什么?
So, what's the topic of discussion?
保罗·艾伦的失踪
The disappearance of Paul Allen.
对
Uh-huh, right.
我没有...
Well, I, um, haven't...
我没有听说过有关失踪的任何事情
I haven't heard anything about the disappearance or anything.
至少在报纸第6页上没有读到
Not on page six, at least.
-我想他的家人希望保密  -可以理解  加点青柠?
-I think his family wants this kept quiet. -Understandable. Lime?
-不  真的  我很好  -你确信? 我能给您拿青柠来
-No, really, I'm okay. -You sure? I can always get you a lime.
就是我的卷宗里面  有些初步问题要问  行吗?
Just some preliminary questions that I need for my own files, okay?
开始吧
Shoot.
-您几岁了? -27
Hold old are you? Twenty-seven.
-您在那里上的学? -哈佛
Where did you go to school? Harvard.
-哈佛商学院  -您的地址?
Then Harvard Business School. Your address?
西81街美国花园大厦
The American Gardens Building, West 81st Street.
-很好  非常好  -谢谢
-Nice. Very nice. -Thanks.
-有关保罗·艾伦  你能告诉我什么? -是我的损失
-What can you tell me about Paul Allen? -I'm at a loss.
他是耶鲁那东西的一部分
He was part of that whole Yale thing.
-"耶鲁那东西"? -对  耶鲁那东西
-"Yale thing"? -Yeah, Yale thing.
"耶鲁那东西"是什么意思?
What do you mean, "Yale thing"?
首先  我认为他很可能  是个隐藏的同性恋
Well, I think for one that he was probably a closet homosexual...
吸了很多可卡因
who did a lot of cocaine.
耶鲁那东西
That "Yale thing."
除了你已经告诉我的信息外
What kind of man was he,
他是什么样的人?
besides the information you've just given?
我希望我这里不是在盘问口供
I hope I'm not being cross-examined here.
-你觉得是吗? -不  真的不是
-You feel like that? -No, not really.
-保罗喜欢去哪儿玩? -去哪儿玩?
-Where did Paul hang out? -Hang out?
对  你知道  去玩
Yeah, you know, hang out.
让我想想  新港
Let me think. Um, the Newport,
哈里书店  福陆蒂餐厅
Harry's, Fluties,
印度支那餐厅  乃尔餐厅  康奈尔俱乐部
Indochina, Nell's, the Cornell Club,
-纽约游艇俱乐部  -他有艘游艇?
-the New York Yacht Club. -He had a yacht?
不  他就是去那里玩
No, he just hung out there.
他在那里上的学?
And where did he go to school?
-你不知道吗? -我就是想看看你知道不知道
-Don't you know this? -I just wanted to know if you know.
在上耶鲁之前  如果我没记错  是圣保罗中学
Before Yale, if I remember correctly, St. Paul's.
听着  我只... 我只是想帮忙
Listen, I just... I just wanna help.
我懂
I understand.
你有什么证人或者指纹吗?
Do you have any witnesses or fingerprints?
他的答录机上有条留言
Well, there's a message on his answering machine
说他去伦敦了
that says he went to London.
-也许他真去了  是吧? -他的女朋友不这么认为
-Well, maybe he did, huh? -His girlfriend doesn't think so.
-但有人在伦敦见到他吗? -实际上  有
-But has anyone seen him in London? -Actually, yes.
但我很难证实
Hmm. But I've had a hard time getting actual verification.
一个叫斯蒂芬·休斯的人说  他在那儿的一家餐厅见过他
A Stephen Hughes said he saw him at a restaurant there.
但我查过了  他把
But I checked it out, and what happened is...
保罗和一个叫做赫伯特·安斯沃茨的人弄混了  所以...
he mistook a Herbert Ainsworth for Paul, so...
他的公寓被抢劫了吗?
Had his apartment been burglarized?
没有  实际上没有
No, actually, it hadn't.
香水没了  一套西装丟了  还有些行李  就这些
Toiletries were missing, a suit was gone, so was some luggage. That's it.
凶杀调查科还没插手  对吧?
I mean, no one's dealing with the homicide squad yet or anything, right?
没有呢  我说过  我不确信
No, not yet. As I said, we're not sure.
基本上  没人见过听说过什么
Basically, no one's seen or heard anything.
-很典型  不是吗? -就是很奇怪
So typical, isn't it? It's just strange.
有一天  一个人走来走去
One day, someone's walking around,
上班  活生生的  然后...
going to work, alive, and then...
没了
Nothing.
人们就这么失踪了
People just disappear.
地球开了口  把他们吞了
The earth just... opens up and swallows them.
太蹊跷了  真蹊跷
Eerie. Really eerie.
听着  你一定要原谅我
Listen, you'll have to excuse me.
过20分钟在四季饭店
I have a lunch meeting with Cliff Huxtable
我与克里夫·胡克斯泰伯有个午餐会议
at Four Seasons in 20 minutes.
四季饭店? 是不是上城区有点太远了?
The Four Seasons? Isn't that a little far uptown?
我是说  你不是要迟到了?
I mean, aren't you gonna be late?
不  是离这里近的那个
No, there's one down here.
-真的? 我不知道  -那里很好
-Oh, really? I didn't know that. -Yeah, it's very good.
听着  如果你想起了什么事  任何信息...
Listen, if anything else occurs to you, any information...
绝对  我百分百听你的
Absolutely. I'm 100 percent with you. Great.
太好了  谢谢你  贝特曼先生
And thanks for your time, Mr. Bateman.
-再见  -再见
Bye-bye. Good-bye.
我在这儿没见过你
I haven't seen you around here.
你没有瞧罢了
You just haven't been lookin'.
你想看我的公寓吗?
Would you like to see my apartment?
我不该看
I'm not supposed to.
你想不想来看我的公寓?
Do you wanna come to my apartment or not?
我不该来看  但我可以破例
I'm not supposed to, but I can make an exception.
你收信用卡吗?
Do you take a credit card?
我开玩笑  来吧  进来
I'm joking. Come on. Get in.
我想要一个20岁出头的金发姑娘
I'd like a girl. Early 20s.
玩两人游戏  两人
Blonde, who does couples. Couples.
我真的不得不强调"金发"  金发
And I really can't stress blonde enough. Blonde.
我是保罗  我的名字叫保罗·艾伦
I'm Paul.
你懂了吗?
My name's Paul Allen. You got that?
你是克里斯蒂  只有叫克里斯蒂的时候  你才回答
You're Christie. You're to respond only to Christie.
清楚了吗?
Is that clear?
你喝的是很好的夏多内白葡萄酒
That's a very fine chardonnay you're drinking.
我要你下面洗干净些
I want you to clean your vagina.
不  从后面洗  蹲下
No. From behind. Get on your knees.
你的身段很好
You have a very nice body.
谢谢  让她上来
Thank you. Send her up.
克里斯蒂  出去擦干净
Christie, get out and dry off.
选件袍子  不要毕扬那件
Choose a robe... not the Bijan...
来与我和我们的客人在客厅喝酒
and come and meet me and our guest in the living room for drinks.
你到了! 真可爱啊
You've arrived. How lovely.
让我把你的大衣挂起来
Let me take your coat.
我是保罗  你来了真好
I'm Paul. How good of you to come.
你的头发不怎么金啊?
Not quite blonde, are you?
有些混杂的金色
More dirty blonde.
我要叫你萨布里娜
I'm gonna call you Sabrina.
我是保罗·艾伦
I'm Paul Allen.
所以
So.
你难道不想知道我是做什么的吗?
Don't you wanna know what I do?
-不  -不  真的不想
-No. -No, not really.
我在华尔街工作  皮尔斯和皮尔斯事务所
Well, I work on Wall Street for Pierce & Pierce.
你听说过吗?
Have you heard of it?
你这个地方真好  保罗
You have a really nice place here, Paul.
你付了多少钱?
How much did you pay for it?
实际上  这不关你事  克里斯蒂
Well, actually, that's none of your business, Christie.
但我保证不便宜
But I can assure you, it certainly wasn't cheap.
不  别抽烟  这里不行
No. No smoking. Not in here.
瓦达特拉芙巧克力?
Varda truffle?
我不想让你喝醉
I don't want you to get drunk,
但那是非常好的夏多内  你却不喝
but that's a very fine chardonnay you're not drinking.
你喜欢菲尔·柯林斯吗?
Do you like Phil Collins?
自从他们发行了  1980年的专辑《Duke》以来
I've been a big Genesis fan ever since the release...
我就特别崇拜创世纪乐队
of their 1980 album Duke.
但那以前
Before that,
我真的不懂他们的作品
I really didn't understand any of their work.
太艺术了  太知识分子气了
It was too artsy, too intellectual.
在《Duke》中
It was on Duke where...
菲尔·柯林斯变得更加突出了
Phil Collins' presence became more apparent.
我想《看不见的接触》
I think Invisible Touch is
是这个组合毫无争议的杰作
the group's undisputed masterpiece.
它是对无形的史诗性思考
It's an epic meditation on intangibility.
同时  它又深化丰富了
At the same time, it deepens and enriches...
随后三张专辑的意义
the meaning of the preceding three albums.
克里斯蒂  脱下袍子
Christie, take off the robe.
听听班克斯  柯林斯  和卢瑟福德的灿烂和声
Listen to the brilliant ensemble playing of Banks, Collins and Rutherford.
你实际上能够听到每种乐器的细微之处
You can practically hear every nuance of every instrument.
萨布里娜  脱掉裙子
Sabrina, remove your dress.
至于作词的精巧和单纯的歌曲创作
In terms of lyrical craftsmanship and sheer songwriting,
这张专辑达到了  专业精神的一个新的巅峰
this album hits a new peak of professionalism.
萨布里娜  你来跳跳舞吧?
Sabrina, why don't you, uh, dance a little.
就拿《忏悔之地》的歌词来讲
Take the lyrics to "Land of Confusion."
在这首歌中  菲尔·柯林斯讨论了
In this song, Phil Collins...
滥用政治权威的问题
addresses the problems of abusive political authority.
《InTooDeep》是80年代  最打动人的流行歌曲
"In Too Deep" is the most moving pop song of the 1980s...
讲的是单一配偶制和承诺
about monogamy and commitment.
这首歌极度振奋人心
The song is extremely uplifting.
歌词积极向上
Their lyrics are as positive and affirmative...
在我听过的摇滚歌曲中是无与伦比的
as, uh, anything I've heard in rock.
克里斯蒂  跪下
Christie, get down on your knees...
让萨布里娜能够看到你的屁眼
so Sabrina can see your asshole.
菲尔·柯林斯的独唱事业
Phil Collins' solo career...
似乎更加商业化
seems to be more commercial,
因此从狭义上更令人满意
and therefore more satisfying in a narrower way,
特别是像《今晚的空中》这些歌
especially songs like "In the Air Tonight"
还有《危情》
and "Against All Odds."
萨布里娜  别瞪着  吃掉
Sabrina, don't just stare at it. Eat it.
但我还认为菲尔·柯林斯
I also think that Phil Collins works best...
在乐队组合里面要比他自己独唱要棒
within the confines of the group than as a solo artist.
我强调"艺术家"这个词
And I stress the word "artist."
这就是《苏苏迪奥》  真正伟大的歌曲
This is "Sussudio."
我个人的最爱
A great, great song. A personal favorite.
看着镜头
Look at the camera.
克里斯蒂  看着镜头
Christie, look at the camera.
别碰那块表
Don't touch the watch.
我们现在能走了吗?
Can we go now?
我们还没完呢
We're not through yet.
如果他们个性好  他们却不特别好看  但谁关心那个呢?
If they have a good personality and they are not great looking, then who fucking cares?
就假设说  好吧  如果他们个性好呢?
Let's just say hypothetically, okay? What if they have a good personality?
我知道  我知道
I know. I know.
姑娘们没有个性好的
There are no girls with good personalities.
好的个性包括
A good personality consists of a chick with a little hard body...
娇小硬朗的身材  能够满足各种性需要
who will satisfy all sexual demands...
而且不会絮絮叨叨
without being too slutty about things...
基本能够让她的臭嘴闭上
and who will essentially keep her dumb fucking mouth shut.
为数不多的个性好的姑娘要聪明
The only girls with good personalities...
也许幽默  或者有些智慧  或者天赋
who are smart or maybe funny or halfway intelligent or talented...
虽然上帝知道这些究竟是些什么意思  就是些丑女
though God knows what the fuck that means... are ugly chicks.
绝对的
Absolutely.
这是因为他们要  弥补他们缺乏吸引力的一面
And this is because they have to make up for how fucking unattractive they are.
你知道  有关女人  艾德金说过
Do you know what Ed Gein said about women?
艾德金? 运河酒吧的侍者长?
Maitre d' at Canal Bar?
不对  50年代威斯康辛州的连环杀手
No, serial killer, Wisconsin, in the 50s.
艾德说了什么?
And what did Ed say?
"当我看到一个漂亮姑娘  沿大街走过来"
"When I see a pretty girl walking down the street, I think two things.
"我想到两件事  我的一部分  想带她出去并对她说"
"One part of me wants to take her out and talk to her,
"一定要乖要甜  对她好"
be real nice and sweet and treat her right."
另一半的他怎么想呢?
And what did the other part of him think?
她的脑袋插在棍子上会是什么样?
What her head would look like on a stick.
伙计们  我想向你们征求一下意见
Hi, guys. I wanna get your opinion on something.
这是我的名片
It's my business card.
我也决心弄张新的
I decided to get a new one too.
那是...
Oh, it's...
很好  路易斯
Very nice, Luis.
谢谢你
Thank you.
皮尔斯和皮尔斯事务所  路易斯·卡鲁瑟斯  副总裁
听着  吃晚餐如何?
Listen, what about dinner?
你就贡献这么多吗? "吃晚餐如何?"
Is that all you ever have to contribute, Van Patten? "What about fucking dinner"?
高兴点儿  贝特曼  怎么了  早上没有做日式按摩?
Cheer up there, Bateman. What's the matter? No shiatsu this morning?
你再那么按我  树桩都被你拉倒了
Keep touching me like that, you'll draw back a stump.
-坚持住  小兄弟  -对不起
-Hold on there, little buddy. -Excuse me.
天啊  帕特立克  为什么在这儿?
God. Patrick. Why here?
我看到你在看我
I've seen you looking at me.
我注意到你身材很好
I've noticed your hot body.
别害臊
Don't be shy.
你不能想象我对此向往已久
You can't imagine how long I've wanted this...
自从在亚利桑那206的  圣诞晚会上就开始了
ever since that Christmas party at Arizona 206.
你带的是红色条纹的阿玛尼领带
You know, the one you were wearing that red-striped paisley Armani tie.
我要你
I want you.
我也要你
I want you too.
-帕特立克  -这是什么?
-Patrick. -What is it?
你去哪儿?
Where are you going?
我要还些录像带
I've gotta return some video tapes.
帕特立克
Patrick!
好吧  伦敦...
Okay, London the...
-伦敦  那个...
London, there's, um,
-保罗·艾伦? -预订了  没  没预订  但...
-Any Paul Allen? -A reservation... No. A reservation, but...
金鲍尔  我一直想跟您谈谈
Kimball! I've been wanting to talk with you.
来我办公室  姬恩  很漂亮的外套  松田的?
Come into my office. Jean, great jacket. Matsuta?
你记得保罗·艾伦  失踪的那天晚上你在哪儿吗?
Do you remember where you were the night of Paul's disappearance,
12月20日?
which was on the 20th of December?
天啊
God.
我猜我很可能去还录像带了
I guess I was probably returning video tapes.
我和一个叫弗拉尼卡的女孩约会
I had a date with a girl named Veronica.
-那不是我知道的情况  -什么?
That's not what I've got. What?
那不是我了解到的情况
That's not the information I've received.
等等  你了解到的信息是什么?
Well, I... Wait. What information have you received?
让我看看
Let me see.
-你和... -我可能错了
-You were with... -Well, I could be wrong.
你最后一次和保罗·艾伦  在一起是什么时候?
When was the last time you were with Paul Allen?
我们去看一出新的音乐剧  叫...
We'd gone to a new musical...
《哦  非洲  勇敢的非洲》  是个可笑的闹剧  就这些
called Oh, Africa, Brave Africa.
我想我们在奥索饭店吃的晚饭
It was a laugh riot. That was about it.
不  佩塔尔... 不  奥索
I think we had dinner at Orso's. No, Peto... No, Orso's.
我希望我提供了信息  很长的一天  有些零散
I hope I've been informative. Long day, a bit scattered.
我也有些累了
I'm a little spent now too.
但过一周吃午饭  怎么样
But how about lunch in a week or so...
等我整理出来所有这些信息了?
when I've sorted out all this information?
很好  好  我同意
Great. Yes, I'd like that.
如果你想出来
And if you could try and pin down where you were...
保罗·艾伦失踪的那晚你在什么地方
the night of Paul Allen's disappearance,
那我的工作就容易多了
it would make my job a lot easier.
绝对的  我同意
Absolutely. I'm with you on that one.
修·刘易斯和新闻乐队
Huey Lewis and the News.
很好的东西  我来这的路上买的  你听过吗?
Great stuff. I just bought it on my way here. You heard it?
从没听过
Never.
我是说  我并不真正喜欢歌手
I mean, I don't really like singers.
-不是歌迷  对吗? -不对  我喜欢音乐
Not a big music fan, huh? No, I like music.
只是他们... 修对我来说听起来太黑色了
Just they're... Huey's too black sounding for me.
每首歌都是
To each his own.
那么  下周一起吃午餐?
So, lunch next week?
我会来的
I'll be there.
你会在复活节前给我打电话吗?
Will you call me before Easter?
也许
Maybe.
你今晚干什么?
What are you doing tonight?
在河流咖啡厅吃晚餐  之后也许  去澳吧喝酒
Dinner at, uh, River Cafe. Au Bar afterwards, maybe.
很好
That's nice.
我从来不知道你抽烟
I never knew you smoked.
你从不注意我
You never noticed.
听着  帕特立克
Listen, Patrick.
我们能谈谈吗?
Can we talk?
你看上去好极了
You look... marvelous.
没什么可说的  你要嫁给路易斯了
There's nothing to say.
那不特别吗?
You're gonna marry Luis. Isn't that special?
帕特立克?
Patrick?
怎么  考特尼?
Yes, Courtney?
如果我在复活节前见不到你  那就祝你节日快乐
If I don't see you before Easter, have a nice one, okay?
你也是
You too.
帕特立克?
Patrick?
怎么?
Yeah?
没什么
Nothing.
现在有这个理论  如果你通过与别人性交
There is this theory now. Listen to me. There is this theory now that if you can catch
能染上爱滋病毒  那就会感染任何病毒
the AIDS virus by having sex with someone who's infected, then you can catch anything.
老年痴呆症  肌肉萎缩  脑溢血  白血病
Alzheimer's, muscular dystrophy, hemophilia, leukemia,
糖尿病  诵读困难
diabetes, dyslexia.
我觉得诵读困难不是病毒吧
I'm not sure, but I don't think dyslexia is a virus.
谁知道呢? 他们也不知道
But who knows? They don't know that.
来证实啊
Prove it.
-天啊! -什么?
-Oh, God. -What?
这是一毫克的代糖
It's a fucking milligram of sweetener.
我想因此而亢奋
I wanna get high off this,
而不是撒在我可恨的燕麦片上
not sprinkle it on my fucking oatmeal. It's definitely weak,
绝对很弱  但我觉得如果  我们放很多就行了
but I have a feeling if we do enough of it, we'll be okay.
你能少放些吗? 我想要吸毒!
Can you keep it down? I'm trying to do drugs.
-混帐! -冷静些  还是放吧
-Fuck you! -Calm down. Let's do it anyway.
好了  如果下个摊位的傻瓜  认为可以的话
That's right. That is if the faggot in the next stall thinks it's okay!
-混帐! -你混帐!
-Fuck you! -Hey, fuck you!
对不起  傻瓜  是类固醇
Sorry, dude. Steroids.
好了  我们干吧
Okay, let's do it.
克雷格去哪儿了?
Where did Craig go?
戈尔巴乔夫在楼下
Well, Gorbachev is downstairs. McDermott went to sign a peace treaty...
麦克德莫特去签美苏和平协议了
between the United States and Russia.
他是在"开放"后面的人
He's the one behind Glasnost.
他说他从事兼并与收购
He said he was in mergers and acquisitions.
你没有糊涂吧?
You're not confused, are you?
真的没有
No, not really.
戈尔巴乔夫不在楼下
Gorbachev is not downstairs. -Karen's right.
卡龙是对的  戈尔巴乔夫不在楼下  他在隧道那儿
Gorbachev's not downstairs. He's at Tunnel.
问我一个问题
Ask me a question.
你做什么工作?
So, what do you do?
我基本上从事谋杀和行刑
I'm into, uh, well, murders and executions, mostly.
-你喜欢吗? -看怎么说  为什么?
-Do you like it? -Well, it depends. Why?
我认识的从事兼并与收购的
Well, most guys I know who work in mergers
大部分人实际上都不喜欢
and acquisitions really don't like it.
那么  你在哪儿工作?
So, where do you work out?
-你以为我傻吗? -什么?
-You think I'm dumb, don't you? -What?
你以为我傻  你以为所有的模特都傻
You think I'm dumb. You think all models are dumb.
不  我真的不那么认为
No. I really don't.
好了  我不介意
That's okay. I don't mind.
你有点甜
There's something sweet about you.
做填字游戏?
Doin' the crossword?
肉  骨头
你需要帮助吗?
You need any help?
姬恩?
Jean?
怎么  帕特立克?
Yes, Patrick?
你愿意陪我吃晚饭吗?
Would you like to accompany me to dinner?
如果你没有其他安排的话
That is, if you're not doing anything.
没有  我没其它安排
Um, no. No, I don't have any plans.
好吧
Well,
这不是巧合吗?
isn't this a coincidence?
-听着  我们应该去哪儿呢? -随便你
Listen, where should we go? Anywhere you want.
不要考虑我想去哪儿  你想去的地方  怎么样?
Let's not think about what I want. How about anywhere you want?
我不知道  帕特立克  我决定不了
I don't know, Patrick. I can't make this decision.
别这样
Come on.
你想去哪儿? 随便选
Where do you wanna go? Anywhere you want,
就说个地方吧  哪儿我都能带你去
just say it. I can get us in anywhere.
你看...
What about...
多西亚如何?
Dorsia?
所以
So,
多西亚是姬恩想去的地方
Dorsia is where Jean wants to go.
我不知道  不  你想去哪儿  我们就去哪儿
Well, I don't know. We'll go wherever you wanna go.
多西亚就很好
Dorsia is fine.
多西亚餐厅  有什么能帮到你?
Dorsia. Yes?
对  订今晚两个人行吗  比如说  9点?
Yeah, can you take two tonight at, oh, let's say 9:00?
-我们全部订满了  -真的? 太好了
-We're totally booked. Really? -That's great.
-不  我说了  已经订满了  -两个人  9点  好极了
-No, I said we are totally booked. -Two at 9:00? Perfect.
回头见
See ya then.
好
Yeah?
你
You're...
穿的衣服还行
dressed okay.
你没有报姓名
You didn't give a name.
他们认识我
They know me.
你7点到我家来接我  喝点东西吧
Why don't you meet me at my place at 7:00 for drinks.
然后  姬恩
And Jean,
你想在我们出门前换衣服
you'll wanna change before we go out.
帕特立克  这真优雅
Patrick, it's so elegant.
景色真美啊
What a wonderful view.
姬恩?
Jean,
刨冰?
sorbet?
谢谢  帕特立克  我想来点儿
Thanks, Patrick. I'd love some.
你要来一口吗?
Do you want a bite?
我在节食  但谢谢你
I'm on a diet. But thank you.
你不需要节食  你开玩笑吧?
You don't need to lose any weight. You're kidding, right?
你看上去很好  非常健美
You look great. Very fit.
总是可以再瘦一点  再好看些
You can always be thinner, look better.
也许我们不该出去吃晚饭
Well, maybe we shouldn't go out to dinner.
我不想破坏你的意志力
I don't wanna ruin your will power.
不  没关系
No, it's all right.
我的控制力反正也不好
I'm not very good at controlling it anyway.
那么  听着
So listen.
你这一辈子真想做什么?
What do you really wanna do with your life?
简单点  总结要点
Just briefly, summarize.
别告诉我你喜欢  做有关小孩子的工作  好吗?
And don't tell me you enjoy working with children, okay?
我喜欢旅行
Well, I'd like to travel and
也许回到学校  但我实在不清楚
maybe go back to school, but I don't really know.
我现在似乎有很多种可能
I'm at a point in my life where there seems to be so many possibilities,
但我不知道  我不确定
but I'm... I don't know... I'm just so unsure.
你有男朋友吗?
Do you have a boyfriend?
不  真的没有
No, not really.
有意思
Interesting.
你在和谁约会吗? 我意思是  认真的那种?
Are you seeing anyone? I mean, seriously?
也许
Maybe.
我不懂
I don't know.
实际上不算
Not really.
姬恩
Jean,
你感到满足吗?
do you feel... fulfilled?
我意思是说  你的人生?
I mean, in your life?
我猜是的  很长时间来  我太专注于工作
I guess I do. For a long time I was too focused on my work.
但现在我真正开始想要改变我自己
But now I've really begun to think about changing myself, you know,
你知道的  发展成长
developing and growing.
成长
Growing.
我很高兴你这么说
I'm glad you said that.
你知道泰德·布恩蒂的第一条狗
Did you know that, uh, Ted Bundy's first dog,
叫做拉希?
a collie, was named Lassie?
-你听说过吗? -谁是泰德·布恩蒂?
-Had you heard this? -Who's Ted Bundy?
忘了吧
Forget it.
-那是什么? -录像带  我来录像用的
-What's that? -Duct tape. I need it for, uh, taping something.
帕特立克?
Patrick,
你想让某人高兴吗?
have you ever wanted to... make someone happy?
什么? 不! 把它放回纸盒子!
What? No! Put it in the carton.
对不起
Sorry.
姬恩?
Jean?
刚你说什么?
What?
让某人高兴
Uh, make someone happy?
你曾经想过吗?
Have you ever wanted to?
我在找...
I'm looking for, uh,
我猜你会说我只想要和一个特殊的人
I guess you could say I just wanna have a meaningful relationship...
来一段有意义的关系
with someone special. Hmm.
帕特立克  帕特立克  我知道你在那里
Patrick? Patrick? I know you're there.
接电话  坏孩子
Pick up the phone, you badboy.
你今晚干什么? 是我  别想躲
What are you up to tonight? It's me. Don't try to hide.
我希望你不是和那些  你挑选的小人物出去
I hope you're not with some little number you picked up
因为你是我的  贝特曼
because you're my Mr. Bateman.
我的邻家男生
My boy next door.
无论如何  你从没像你保证的那样  给我打电话
Anyway, you never called me and you said you would,
关于这个  我会给姬恩  留个口信来提醒你
and I'll leave a message for Jean about this, too, to remind you,
但我们和美兰妮和泰勒吃晚饭
but we're having dinner with Melania and Taylor.
你认识美兰妮  她也去了甜蔷薇
You know Me lania. She went to Sweet Briar.
我们会在康奈尔俱乐部碰头
And we're meeting at the Cornell Club,
我明早给你打电话  甜心
so I'll call you tomorrow morning, honey.
对不起  我知道你憎恨这个
Oops. Sorry. I know you hate that.
再见  帕特立克  再见  不可一世的首席执行官先生
Bye, Patrick. Bye, Mr. Big Time C.E.O.
再见
Bye-bye.
那是伊芙琳吗?
Was that Evelyn?
你还在和她约会?
Are you still seeing her?
对不起  我没有权利问这个
I'm sorry. I have no right to ask that.
你要我走开吗?
Do you want me to go?
对
Yeah.
我觉得我控制不了自己
I don't think I can control myself.
我知道  我该走了
I know. I should go.
我知道我总是与  名草有主的男人纠缠不清
I know I have a tendency to get involved with unavailable men.
我是说
I mean,
你要我走吗?
do you want me to go?
我想如果你留下来
I think if you stay,
就会发生坏事
something bad will happen.
我觉得我会伤害你
I think I might hurt you.
你不想受伤害  对吗?
You don't wanna get hurt, do you?
是  我不想
No. No, I guess not.
我不想浑身青紫
I don't wanna get bruised.
你是对的  我应该走了
You're right. I should go.
别忘了你明天中午有个饭局
Oh. Don't forget you have a lunch date tomorrow
和唐纳德·金鲍尔  在史密斯和沃伦斯基餐厅
with Donald Kimball at Smith and Wolenski's.
谢谢
Thanks.
我完全忘记了
It slipped my mind completely.
那么
So,
他失踪的那天夜里
the night he disappeared...
你想起来自己去哪儿了?
any new thoughts about what you did?
不确信  我洗了个澡
Not sure. Um, I had a shower...
吃了些刨冰
and some sorbet?
我想你把你的约会弄混了
I think you're getting your dates mixed up.
那你认为保罗那晚去哪儿了?
But how? Where do you place... Paul that night?
按照他的日期记录  这是得到了他秘书证实了的
According to his date book, and this was verified by his secretary,
他和马克斯·哈尔波斯特拉姆  一起吃晚饭
he had dinner with Marcus Halberstram.
-然后? -我问了他
-And? -I questioned him.
-马克斯  -对  他否认
-Marcus? -Yes, and he denies it, though,
起初  他不能确定
at first, he couldn't be sure.
-但他否认了? -对
-But he denied it. -Yes.
-马克斯有不在场证明? -对
-Well, does Marcus have an alibi? -Yes.
-真的吗? 你确信? -我查过了  是清白的
-He does? You're sure? -I checked it out. It's clean.
现在  你当时在哪儿?
Now, where were you?
马克斯在哪儿?
Where was Marcus?
他没有和保罗·艾伦在一起
He wasn't with Paul Allen.
他和谁在一起?
Who was he with? He was...
他在亚特兰蒂斯
at Atlantis... with...
和克雷格  福里德里克
Craig McDermott, Frederick Dibble,
哈里  乔治
Harry Newman, George Butner...
还有你在一起
and... you.
对了  当然
Oh, right, yeah. Of course.
他本来希望保罗·艾伦能来
We had wanted Paul Allen to come,
但他另有计划
but he had made plans.
我猜  那之后的第二天晚上  我与维多利亚吃的晚饭
And I guess I had dinner with Victoria the following night.
个人角度看  我想这个家伙有点疯
Personally, I think the guy went a little nutso.
一时精神分裂似的
Split town for a while.
也许他的确去了伦敦  观光  喝酒什么的
Maybe he did go to London, sightseeing, drinking, whatever.
不管怎样  我相当确信他迟早会露面的
Anyway, I'm pretty sure he'll turn up sooner or later.
我是说  想到他的一个朋友杀了他
I mean, to think that one of his friends killed him
无缘无故  太蹊跷了
for no reason whatsoever would be too ridiculous.
不是吗  帕特立克?
Isn't that right, Patrick?
克里斯蒂  克里斯蒂!
Christie. Christie.
我不确信能做这个  上次我就进了急诊室
I'm not so sure about this. I had to go to Emergency after last time.
这不会像上次的  我保证
This won't be anything like last time. I promise.
我觉得不行
I don't think so.
就是坐进豪华房车和我谈上一分钟
Just come in the limo and talk to me for a minute.
司机在这儿  你是安全的
The driver's here. You'll be safe.
绝对不像上次  我保证
Nothing like last time. Promise.
好吧
All right.
你看上去很好  去哪儿了?
So, you're looking great. How have you been?
上次之后  我实际上需要个小手术
Well, I actually might need surgery after last time.
-真的? -我朋友告诉我  我应该找个律师
-Really? -My friend told me I should maybe even get a lawyer.
律师太复杂
Lawyers are so complicated.
别那么做
Don't do that.
拿上这张支票
Here's a check.
现在一半  完事一半
Uh-uh. Half now, half later.
好  你的名字叫克里斯蒂
Okay, your name is Christie.
我们会见我的一个朋友  伊丽莎白
We're meeting a friend of mine, Elizabeth.
她很快就会来我的新公寓  来加入我们
She'll be joining us in my new apartment shortly.
你会喜欢她的  她是很好的女孩
You'll like her. She's a very nice girl.
你看上去很眼熟  你去过道顿吗?
You look really familiar. Did you go to Dalton?
我想我在冲浪酒吧遇到过你  对吗? 和斯派西在一起?
I think I met you at Surf Bar, didn't I? With Spicey?
也许不是和斯派西  但绝对是冲浪酒吧  对吗?
Well, maybe not with Spicey, but definitely at SurfBar. You know, SurfBar.
无论如何  冲浪酒吧现在很糟
Anyway, Surf Bar sucks now. It's terrible.
我曾去那里参加过马尔科姆·福布斯的生日宴会  我的天  请
Went to a birthday party there for Malcolm Forbes. Oh, my God, please.
这比你另一个公寓更好
This is nicer than your other apartment.
不那么好
Oh, it's not that nice.
你们俩什么时候遇到的?
Where did you two meet?
天啊  我们见过面  在...
Oh, God. We met at...
天啊  在肯塔基州的达比  85或者86年
oh, God, at the Kentucky Derby in '85, or '86.
你与那个大胸脯的艾利森一起
You were hanging out with that bimbo Allison Poole.
-很热辣的娘们  -你什么意思? 她是很热辣的娘们?
-Hot number. -What do you mean, She was a hot number?
如果你有个白金卡的话  她就给你口交
If you had a platinum card, she'd give you a blowjob. Need I say more?
这个姑娘在日晒沙龙工作  我还要说更多吗?
This girl worked in a tanning salon.
你做什么?
What do you do?
她是我的
She's my...
表妹
cousin.
她是
Uh-huh. She's from...
法国人
France.
你的电话呢? 我要给哈里打电话
Where's your phone? I've gotta call Harley.
你夏天在哪儿? 南安普敦?
Where do you summer, South Hampton?
不
No.
-天啊  是他的留言机  -伊丽莎白  现在是早上3点
-Oh, God, it's his machine. -It's 3:00 in the morning.
他是个可恨的毒贩子  这是他的活跃时间
He's a goddamn drug dealer. These are his peak hours.
-别告诉他你在这儿  -我为什么要告诉他?
-Don't tell him you're here. -Why would I?
这味道真怪
This tastes weird.
哈里  是我  我需要你的服务
Harley, it's me. I need your services.
怎么理解都行
Translate that however you want.
我在...
I'm at...
-你在保罗·艾伦那儿  -谁?
-Paul Allen's. -Who?
-保罗·艾伦  -我要号码  傻瓜
-Paul Allen's. -I want the number, idiot.
无论如何  我在保罗·诺曼这儿  我过一会儿给你打
Anyway, I'm at Paul Norman's and I'll try you again later.
如果我明晚没有在运河酒吧看到你  我就派我的发型师去找你
And if I don't see you at Canal Bar tomorrow night I'm gonna sic my hairdresser on you.
你知道那家伙失踪了吗? 他不是在皮尔斯和皮尔斯工作吗?
Did you know that guy who disappeared? Didn't he work at Pierce & Pierce?
-他是你的朋友吗? -不
-Was he a friend of yours? -No.
你有可乐吗? 或者酣乐欣?
Do you have any coke? Or Halcyon?
我要服酣乐欣
I would take a Halcyon.
听着
Listen.
我就想让
I would just like to see...
你们俩相处得好
the two of you... get it on.
这怎么啦?
What's wrong with that?
完全无病
It's totally disease free.
-帕特立克  你疯了  -别了
-Patrick, you're a lunatic. -Come on.
你不觉得克里斯蒂很有魅力吗?
Don't you find Christie attractive?
别下流了  我没心情说下流话
Let's not get lewd. I'm in no mood for a lewd conversation.
来吧
Come on.
我觉得这会让你兴奋
I think it'd be a turn-on.
他一直这么做吗?
Does he do this all the time?
克里斯蒂  你没喝你的酒
Christie, you're not drinking your wine.
你说你从没和女孩上过床?
Are you telling me you've never gotten it on with a girl?
没有  我不是同性恋
No. I'm not a lesbian.
为什么你会觉得我喜欢这个?
Why would you think I would be into that?
你去过萨拉·劳伦斯那里  这就是理由之一
Well, you went to Sarah Lawrence for one thing.
那些都是萨拉·劳伦斯的男人  帕特立克
Those are Sarah Lawrence guys, Patrick.
你让我感觉古怪
You're making me feel weird.
你知道
Did you know...
惠特尼·休斯敦的首张大碟
that Whitney Houston's debut LP...
就叫《惠特尼·休斯敦》
called simply Whitney Houston...
里面有4首排行第一的单曲?
had four number-one singles on it?
你知道吗  克里斯蒂?
Did you know that, Christie?
你真的听惠特尼·休斯敦的歌?
You actually listen to Whitney Houston?
你有惠特尼·休斯敦的CD?
You own a Whitney Houston CD?
还不止一张?
More than one?
这么多很好的曲目  难以选出最爱
It's hard to choose a favorite among so many great tracks.
但是《最伟大的爱》
But the "Greatest Love Of All"
就是人类创作出的  最杰出的一首
is one of the best, most powerful songs...
这是有关自我保护和尊严的歌曲
ever written about self-preservation and dignity.
其永恒的主题  跨越所有疆界
It's universal message crosses all boundaries...
为人们注入希望
and instills one with the hope
改善自己永远不迟
that it's not too late to better ourselves.
因为  伊丽莎白
Since, Elizabeth,
在我们居住的这个世界上
it's impossible in this world
不可能相互怜悯
we live in to empathize with others,
我们只能顾影自怜
we can always empathize with ourselves.
这是重要的信息
It's an important message.
真正残酷
Crucial, really.
在这张专辑里  优美地进行了诠释
And it's beautifully stated on the album.
别在脸上  你这个婊子!
Not the face! You bitch,
别在该死的脸上  你这个烂婊子!
not the fucking face, you piece of bitch trash!
我想要一个实在的承诺
I want a firm commitment.
我想  伊芙琳
I think, um, Evelyn,
我们已经失去联系了
that, uh, we've lost touch.
为什么? 出了什么事?
Why? What's wrong?
我进行大规模行凶的需要
My need to engage in homicidal behavior...
不能得以纠正
on a massive scale cannot be corrected,
但我必须有其他方式来满足我的需要
but I have no other way to fulfill my needs.
-我们需要谈谈  -谈什么  帕特立克?
We need to talk. Talk about what, Patrick?
一切都结束了  伊芙琳
It's over, Evelyn.
一切都结束了
It's all over.
棘手啊  棘手  对不起我提起了婚礼
Touchy, touchy. I'm sorry I brought up the wedding.
我们别提这个问题好吗? 现在我们去喝咖啡吧?
Let's just avoid the issue, all right? Now, are we having coffee?
我特别认真  结束了  我们
I'm fucking serious. It's fucking over, us.
别开玩笑
This is no joke.
我认为我们不要再见面了
Uh, I don't think we should see each other anymore.
但是你的朋友也是我的朋友  我的朋友也是你的朋友
But your friends are my friends and my friends are your friends.
我真的认为没有希望  你有点儿...
I really don't think it would work. You have a little something...
我知道你的朋友也是我的朋友
I know that your friends are my friends, and, uh...
我想过了
and I've thought about that.
你要他们好了
You can have 'em.
-你真是认真的  对吗? -对
-You're really serious, aren't you? -Yes, lam.
过去呢? 我们的过去呢?
What about the past? Our past?
我们从来没有共同的过去
We never really shared one.
-你疯了  -没有
-You're inhuman.- No.
我还有理智
I'm in touch with humanity.
伊芙琳  对不起
Evelyn, I'm, uh, sorry.
我只是...
I just, uh...
你对我并不特别重要
You're not terribly important to me.
我的天呀  不!
Oh, no!
不! 不!
No. No, Patrick.
我知道我有时候行为古怪
I know my behavior can be... erratic sometimes.
你想要我做什么? 你想要什么?
What do you want me to do? What is it that you want?
如果你真的想要为我做什么  那就别在这里丟人现眼了
If you really wanna do something for me, then stop making this scene right now.
-天啊  我不相信  -我要走了
-Oh, God, I can't believe this. -I'm leaving.
我已经考虑了形势  我要走了
I've assessed the situation, and I'm going.
-你去哪儿? -就是离开
-Where are you going? -I'm just leaving.
去哪儿?
But where?
我要去还些录像带
I have to return some videotapes.
这里  小猫
Here, kitty, kitty.
喂喂我  一只迷途小猫
我的天  你在做什么?
Oh, my God. What are you doing?
住手!
Stop that.
放下武器! 立即放下!
Drop the weapon! Drop it now!
趴到地上! 放下...
Get on the ground! Put your...
熬夜吗  史密斯先生?
Burning the midnight oil, Mr. Smith?
别忘了签到
Hey, now don't forget to sign in.
哈罗德  我是贝特曼  帕特立克·贝特曼
Howard, it's Bateman. Patrick Bateman.
你是我的律师  所以我想你应该知道  我已经杀了很多人
You're my lawyer, so I think you should know I've killed a lot of people.
在上城区的公寓里杀了些应召女郎
Some escort girls in an apartment uptown,
还有些无家可归者  或许5到10个
uh, some homeless people, maybe five or ten,
我在中央公园遇到的  一个纽约大学的女生
an N.Y.U. girl I met in Central Park.
我把她放在某个  甜圈圈店后面的停车场了
I left her at a parking lot behind some doughnut shop.
我杀了贝特尼  我以前的女朋友  用钉子抢
I killed Bethany, my old girlfriend, with a nail gun.
还有一些人  有些带狗的老家伙
And-And-And then some man, s-s-some old faggot with a dog.
上周  我... 杀了另一个女孩
Last week, I, uh... I killed another girl
用一把链子锯
with a chain saw.
我不得不杀  她几乎跑掉
I had to. She almost got away.
还有些人  我记不得了
And... Someone else there. I can't remember,
也许是个模特  但她也死了
maybe a model... She's dead too.
还有保罗·艾伦
And, uh, Paul Allen.
我用一把斧头砍了保罗·艾伦的脸部
I killed Paul Allen with an ax in the face.
在地狱厨房的一个浴盆里  销毁了他的尸体
His body is dissolving in a bathtub in Hell's Kitchen.
我不想在这里留下任何东西
I don't wanna leave anything out here.
我猜我大约杀了20个人
I guess I've killed maybe... 20 people.
也许是40人
Maybe 40!
我有很多录像带
I have tapes of a lot of it.
有些姑娘看过这些录像带
Some of the girls have seen the tapes.
我甚至...
I even, um,
我吃了他们一些人的脑子
I ate some of their brains...
我尝试着烹饪
and I tried to cook a little.
今晚  我...
Tonight, I, uh...
我就是必须要杀很多人  然后...
I just had to kill a lot of people! And, um,
我不确信这次能够逃脱
I'm not sure I'm gonna get away with it... this time.
所以我的意思是...
So, uh... I mean,
我猜
I guess...
我相当...
I'm a pretty, uh...
我猜  我相当有病
I mean, I guess I'm a pretty sick guy.
所以
So,
如果你明天回来
if you get back tomorrow,
我会去哈里酒吧
I may show up at Harry's Bar.
所以  你知道
So, you know,
睁大你的眼睛
keep your eyes open.
你是我订的2点女郎?
Are you my 2:00?
不
No.
我能帮你吗?
Can I help you?
我在找保罗·艾伦的家
I'm looking for... Paul Allen's place.
他不住在这儿吗?
Doesn't he... live here?
不  他不住这儿
No, he doesn't.
你确信?
You sure?
你看了《纽约时报》的广告了吗?
You saw the ad in the Times?
没有  对  我是说  看了
No. Yeah. I mean, yeah.
-在《纽约时报》上  -《纽约时报》上没有广告
-In the Times. -There was no ad in the Times.
我觉得你该走了
I think you should go now.
但我想...
But I think...
我想知道这里发生了什么
I wanna know what happened here.
请别找麻烦
Don't make any trouble, please.
我建议你走吧
I suggest you go.
别回来
Don't come back.
我不会的
I won't.
别担心
Don't worry.
帕特立克·贝特曼办公室
Patrick Bateman's office.
-姬恩  我需要帮助  -帕特立克  是你吗?
-Jean? I need help. -Patrick, is that you?
姬恩  我不是...
Jean, I'm not...
克雷格·迈克德莫特打了电话  他要见你
Craig McDermott called. Wants to meet you,
戴维·冯·帕顿和蒂姆·布莱斯  在哈里酒吧喝酒
David Van Patten and Tim Bryce at Harry's.
天啊
Oh, God.
你说什么  你这个笨娘们?
What did you say, you dumb bitch?
-帕特立克  我听不见你说话  -我在做什么?
-Patrick, I can't hear you. -What am I doing?
你在哪儿  帕特立克? 出了什么事?
Where are you, Patrick? What's wrong?
姬恩  我觉得我不行了
I don't think I'm gonna make it, Jean, to the, uh,
今天下午来不了办公室了
office this afternoon.
为什么?
Why?
就是说  不!
Just say no!
帕特立克? 你还好吗?
What is it, Patrick? Are you all right?
别这么悲伤!
Stop sounding so fucking sad.
天啊!
Jesus!
一张三人桌
That's a table for three.
贝特曼  你看上去很疲惫  上班很不顺吗?
Bateman, you're looking wild-eyed. Rough day?
听着  布莱斯回来了  他在喝矿泉水
Hey, look. Bryce is back and he's drinking mineral water.
他改头换面了  但还是订不到桌子  来救他的命
He's a changed man, except for he still can't a reservation to save his life.
为什么你不试试武司特150号?
Why don't you just try 150 Wooster?
我订不到哪儿也不去
I'm not going anywhere unless we have a reservation.
马戏团餐馆  佛拉明戈东  牡蛎酒吧
Le Cirque, Flamingo East, Oyster Bar.
别了  傻瓜  我们来找馆子
Come on, faggots. Let's get a "res."
穿上你的衬衫  也许不必系肩带
Keep your shirt on. Maybe lose the suspenders.
需要一个8点半的预订
Need a reservation for 8:30.
对不起  先生们  马上就来
Excuse me, gentlemen. Right back.
10点都订不上
10:00 would not be any good. No.
就给他们打电话吧
Just fucking call them.
-给我电话  我来打  -我给你打回来
-Give me the phone. I'll do it. -I'll call you back.
面对现实  日本人在90年代底  就会拥有这个国家的大部分了
Face it. The Japanese will own most of this country by the end of the '90s.
闭嘴  卡恩斯  他们不会的
Shut up, Carnes. They will not.
那么  哈罗德  你收到我留言了?
So, uh, Harold, did you get my message?
天啊  当然  真好笑
Jesus, yes. That was hilarious.
-那是你吗? -对  当然
-That was you, wasn't it? -Yeah, naturally.
贝特曼杀死了艾伦和众应召女郎  真是太棒了
Bateman killing Allen and the escort girls. That's fabulous.
-太丰富了  -你究竟是什么意思?
-That's rich. -What exactly do you mean?
你的留言  顺便说  戴维斯  辛西亚如何了?
The message you left. By the way, Davis, how's Cynthia?
-你还在和她约会吧? -等等  哈罗德  你什么意思?
-You're still seeing her, right? -W-Wait, Harold. What do you mean?
对不起  没什么  见到你很高兴
Excuse me. Nothing. It's good to see you.
那是爱德华·托尔斯吗?
Is that Edward Towers?
等等
Carnes, wait. Uh...
戴维斯
Davis,
我不随便说别人坏话
I'm not one to bad-mouth anyone.
你的笑话很好玩  但等等
Your joke was amusing. But come on, man.
你有个致命错误
You had one fatal flaw
贝特曼是个大混蛋
Bateman is such a dork.
这么一个乏味  没想法的轻量级选手
Such a boring, spineless lightweight.
如果你说布莱斯或麦克德莫特... 除此之外  很好玩
Now, if you said Bryce or Mc Dermott. Otherwise, it was amusing.
现在请原谅  我真要走了
Now, if you'll excuse me, I really must be going.
等等
Wait. Uh...
停步
Stop.
是我做的  卡恩斯
I did it, Carnes.
我杀了他
I killed him.
我是帕特立克·贝特曼
I'm Patrick Bateman.
我把艾伦的脑袋剁下来了
I chopped Allen's fucking head off.
我在你电话上留的言  都是真的
The whole message I left on your machine was true.
对不起  我真的必须要走了
Excuse me. I really must be going now.
不  听着
No. No, listen.
你不知道我是谁吗?
Don't you know who I am?
我不是戴维斯  我是帕特立克·贝特曼
I'm not Davis. I'm Patrick Bateman.
我们总在电话上聊天的
We talk on the phone all the time.
你不认识我了?
Don't you recognize me?
你是我的律师
You're my lawyer.
现在  傻瓜们
Now, Carnes, listen.
听着
Listen
非常  非常仔细地听着
very, very carefully.
我杀了保罗·艾伦
I killed Paul Allen,
我喜欢这么做
and I liked it.
我讲得再清楚不过了
I can't make myself any clearer.
不可能更直白了
But that's simply not possible.
我不觉得这个可笑
And I don't find this funny anymore.
本来不应该是个笑话
It never was supposed to be.
-为什么不可能? -就是不可能
-Why isn't it possible? -It's just not.
为什么不可能  你这个愚蠢的混帐?
Why not, you stupid bastard?
因为就在10天前  我和保罗·艾伦还在伦敦吃过两顿晚饭
Because I had dinner with Paul Allen twice in London just ten days ago.
不  你...
No, you...
不会吧
didn't.
现在  请你稍等
Now, if you'll excuse me.
铿锵玫瑰
我们见过互不信任的恶果
We've seen the results of that mistrust...
谎言  分歧和错误  纷纷呈现
in the form of lies, provisions in the states.
我们需要找到合作的方式
We need to find a way to cooperate
而对外关系
while realizing foreign policy...
不能由委员会来负责
can't be run by committee.
我相信我们通过合作
And I believe there's now the growing sense...
会成就更多事情
that we can accomplish more by cooperating.
最后  这也许是坏事中的好事
And in the end, this maybe the eventual blessing in disguise...
脱离伊朗问题的混乱
to come out of the Iran-Contra mess.
他怎么能这样撒谎?
How can he lie like that?
-他怎么能提那桩丑事? -什么丑事?
-How can he pull that shit? -What shit?
现在我们预订哪家餐馆?
Now, where do we have reservations at?
我其实不饿  但我想还是订个地方
I'm not really hungry, but I'd like to have reservations someplace.
你怎么能这么...
How can you be so fucking,
我不知道... 很酷吧?
I don't know, cool about it?
有些家伙天生很酷  我猜
Some guys are just born cool, I guess.
贝特曼?
Bateman?
你们究竟胡扯什么呢?
What are you so fucking zany about?
我就是个四处为营的人
I'm just a happy camper.
摇滚青年!
Rockin' and a rollin'!
兄弟! 看
Oh, brother, look.
他把自己说成  老不中用的家伙
He presents himself as this harmless old codger,
但内心...
but inside...
但内心并不重要
But inside doesn't matter.
内心? 对了 内心
Inside? Yes, inside.
不管你信不信  布莱斯  我们实际上听你的
Believe or not, Bryce, we're actually listening to you.
来啊  贝特曼  你怎么想?
Come on, Bateman. What do you think?
我才不关心呢
Whatever.
是谁的烂主意订了干啤?
Whose moronic idea was it to order dry beers?
我需要来杯威士忌
I need a scotch.
当我向美国上诉法庭举报他的时候
When I named him to the United States Court of appeals
没有什么障碍需要跨越
There are no more barriers to cross.
我们共同之处是无法控制的
All I have in common with the uncontrollable
疯狂恶毒的一面
and the insane, the vicious and the evil,
我所造成的伤害  以及我对此的冷酷漠然
all the mayhem I have caused and my utter indifference toward it,
都已经被我所逾越
I have now surpassed.
我的痛苦持久而深刻
My pain is constant and sharp...
我不希望人人都  拥有更加美好的世界
and I do not hope for a better world for anyone.
实际上  我希望将我的痛苦  强加给别人
In fact, I want my pain to be inflicted on others.
我希望没人能够逃脱
I want no one to escape.
但即使承认了这些
But even after admitting this,
我的心依然没有解脱
there is no catharsis.
我依然躲避着应得的惩罚
My punishment continues to elude me...
我对自己没有更深的了解
and I gain no deeper knowledge of myself.
我的讲述中不再有新东西了
No new knowledge can be extracted from my telling.
这个忏悔毫无意义
This confession has meant... nothing.